

Bhanu Chavala

Thone: +65 98244028

♣ Email: kcbpcc@gmail.com

S Visa/Passport: Singapore PR, Indian Passport

Preferred location: Singapore / Hyderabad

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kcbpcc/

Profile

23 years of SAP technology and SAP customer engagement experience with worldwide SAP customers with various roles and responsibilities in SAP Asia Pte Ltd, Singapore

Current role: **Regional Director -** Customer Engagement, S4HANA Cloud adoption - Asia Pacific & Japan

SAP Certified (10+) in most of SAP Technology area & **Certified Microsoft Azure** for SAP Workloads Specialty

What I will bring:

Proven record of accomplishment in a multitude of business domains including business development, deal support, presales, customer engagement, Implementations, upgrades, transformations, negotiation and escalation management, ideation to rollout, crisis management, project, and program management along with effective stakeholder collaboration.

What I am looking:

Long-term and challenging role where I can passionately add immense value with my vast variety of technology and business skill sets.

Experience

SAP Asia Pte Ltd, Singapore	2001 to Present
Role: Regional Director - Customer Engagements Team: SAP Customer Value experience S4HANA Cloud adoption	(2020 - 2024)
Role: Director Technology - Partner Engagements Team: SAP Maintenance Go-to Market	(2016 - 2020)
Role: Program Manager - Customer Value experience Tools Team: SAP Global Upgrade Office	(2013 - 2016)
Role: Technical Project Manager - Customer upgrade Journey Team: SAP Upgrade competency Center	(2010 - 2013)
Roles: Customer Escalation Architect Technical Quality Manager SAP Platinum Technology Consultant (Basis) SAP Senior Support Consultant (Basis) Team: SAP Active Global Support	(2001 - 2010)

Technical Skills

- ✓ SAP Certified Technology SAP S/4HANA Conversion and SAP System Upgrade
- ✓ Microsoft Certified: Azure for SAP Workloads Specialty
- ✓ Certified SAP E2E Program Manager (Technical **Upgrade Management**)
- ✓ Certified SAP E2E Application Management (End to End Change control Management)
 ✓ Certified SAP E2E Application Management (End to End Root Cause Analysis)
- ✓ SAP Certified Technology System Administration (SAP HANA) with SAP NetWeaver
- ✓ Microsoft Certified: Azure Database Administrator Associate
- ✓ Certified SAP NetWeaver Support Consultant✓ Certified SAP R/3 Service consultant
- ✓ Certified SAP Technology Consultant (SAP NetWeaver (Exchange Infrastructure)
- ✓ Certified SAP Technology Consultant (SAP NetWeaver Portal)
- ✓ Microsoft Certified Professional (MSSQL)
- ✓ Microsoft Certified Professional (Windows)

Education

MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION - 1996

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY - 1994



Experience with SAP Asia Pte Ltd (2001 to 2024)

At SAP, I exceled in customer engagement by deciphering customer personas and segmentation. allowing me to create personalized experiences that foster lasting relationships. I actively gathered and utilized customer feedback to strategically position SAP products in the market.

From ideation to rollout, I led the process of fostering creativity, conducting market research, and driving innovation through design thinking and prototyping. This ensured seamless transitions from concept to reality for our projects.

I leveraged my expertise in SAP technology consulting to deliver innovative solutions that drive value and innovation for our clients. I blended business acumen with technical expertise to craft tailored strategies that met our clients' needs.

Negotiation was a key aspect of my role, where I applied principled negotiation principles, conducted thorough BATNA analyses, and employed win-win negotiation techniques to secure favourable outcomes for our company.

In times of crisis, I rely on a well-crafted crisis management plan to develop communication strategies and assume a leadership role to navigate challenges with poise and resilience.

I am also proficient in project and program management, where I lay the foundation for success through effective initiation and planning. By defining clear scopes and structuring work breakdowns, I ensure efficiency and strategic alignment with organizational objectives.

Stakeholder collaboration is a strength of mine, as I facilitate communication and alignment between cross-functional teams and stakeholders. My adept communication skills ensure successful adoption of SAP initiatives that contribute meaningfully to our company's overarching goals.

Highlighted Tasks

I have been a delivery lead for innumerable number of impactful tools. Notably, I ideated the Business Scenario Recommendations Report (BSR), which is a door opener for discovering SAP S4HANA's value.

I have been a public speaker numerous times highlighting Innovation & support value at various events like SAP FKOM / SAP SKOM / SAP Teched and other internal and external events.

Overseen and supervised internal and customer SAP implementation projects relating to migration.

Handled hundreds of customer escalations all over the world being onsite during mission-critical situations / production downtimes.

Conducted hundreds of customer workshops all over the APAC region.

Designed multiple customer engagement approaches such as customer lifecycle management and overseen delivery.

Ran hundreds of partner workshops to improve service delivery as well as the VARD support.

Delivered numerous SAP services to customers such as Go-live Support/Cutover Support.

Addressed thousands of customer/OSS issues and provided action plans and solutions.

Personal details

Full Name: KAMMA CHAVALA BHANU PRAKASH CHAKRAVARTHY CHOWDARY

Nationality: Indian & Singapore PR

Marital status: Married | Children: 2 Boys